So, let's return to the main subject of this lesson,
我们回到这节课的主要话题上
which is factor models of risk.
即风险因子模型
So, how do we use PCA to create a factor model of risk?
如何使用 PCA 创建风险因子模型？
What are our data?
我们的数据是什么？
They are a set of time series of stock returns for many, many companies.
它们是很多很多公司的股票收益率时间序列集合
Our main motivations for using PCA are to reduce the dimensionality of these data
我们使用 PCA 的主要目的是降低这些数据的维度
and also find a representation of them that captures a maximum amount of their variance.
并且找到一种能够尽量捕获最多方差的表示法
We'll use this representation or model of risk later when
之后在优化问题中最小化风险时
we seek to minimize risk as part of an optimization problem.
我们将使用这种表示法或风险模型
We're going to be talking about a lot of matrix multiplications here,
我们将遇到很多矩阵乘法运算
so I'm going to try to always write down the dimensions.
我会一直记下维度
I think keeping track of the dimensions will help you keep track of what's going on.
记下维度有助于记录所发生的情况
It's certainly helps me.
反正对我有帮助
When we use a factor model, remember,
在使用因子模型时
we have a representation of the returns that looks like this.
收益率公式是这样的
In order to produce a factor model of risk using PCA,
为了使用 PCA 创建风险因子模型
we need to look at what the PCA algorithm gives
我们需要查看 PCA 算法的结果
us and map its outputs to each of these matrices;
并将输出对应到每个矩阵
the factor exposures, factor returns,
即因子暴露度 因子收益率
and the idiosyncratic risk matrix.
以及特质风险矩阵
So, let's look at what these symbols represent in terms of matrices.
我们来看看这些符号所代表的矩阵
The returns matrix has dimensions of number of companies by number of time points.
收益率矩阵的维度是公司数量 x 时间点数量
The matrix of factor exposures has dimensions,
因子暴露度矩阵的维度是
number of companies by number of factors.
公司数量 x 因子数量
The matrix of factor returns has dimensions
因子收益率矩阵的维度是
of number of factors by number of time points.
因子数量 x 时间点数量
Finally, the matrix of specific risk has
最后 特有风险矩阵的维度是
dimensions number of companies by number of time points.
公司数量 x 时间点数量
Let's take a look at what we get from running the PCA algorithm.
我们看看运行 PCA 算法后的结果
Remember that PCA finds a new basis for the data.
PCA 会从数据中寻找新的基
If we keep all the PCs,
如果我们保留所有 PC
then multiplying the representation of the data in the PC language by
那么将用 PC 语言表示的数据乘以 PC 矩阵
the matrix of PCs completely recreates the data in the original basis.
会完全重现用原始基表示的数据
On the other hand, if we drop some of the PCs then multiplying
另一方面 如果我们丢弃某些 PC
the data matrix in the new basis by the matrix of PCs almost recreates the data.
那么将用新基表示的数据矩阵乘以 PC 矩阵几乎会重现数据
This is the compressed representation of the data.
这是数据的紧凑表示法
If we add in what's leftover,
如果我们包含剩下的部分
then we have a complete representation of the data.
就会获得数据的完整表示
Now, this is looking a lot like
这个看起来很像
the factor representation we discussed a little bit earlier.
之前讨论的因子表示法
In fact, we're just going to use this as our factor model.
实际上 我们会将这个当做因子模型